Aleksandar Jovkovic

Software Engineer at International Game Technology

Summary

Currently I am an engineer and I recently obtained an MBA. My long term goal is to become a CEO and make a difference in the world one day so I believe having an MBA will help me get there. Throughout my MBA program I have developed many skills that will help me identify and solve hard and exciting problems, understand a business and its goals, have great presentation and communication skills, and be a great leader.

Great leaders communicate well, they are passionate, they inspire others, they are creative, they are patient and they are honest. I believe that I possess these and many other qualities that make a leader effective and worth following. I love taking on a challenge and learning something new because as a result I always grow and become a better person. I work hard every day and I believe that today should be better then yesterday was.

I stay positive in the best and worst situations because it always helps me make good progress. I love trying new things and I love a good routine. I worked hard my whole life to get to where I am today and I do not believe in failure. Whenever I fail I see it as a positive thing because I accomplish and learn something new. It also helps me narrow down which skills and areas I need to improve on. Whenever I succeed I feel accomplished and intrinsically rewarded.

I never want to stop learning or being challenged in and out of my comfort zone. I enjoy listening to motivating speakers, reading about new technologies, learning about advancements in medicine, and keeping up with the stock market. I love working with people because it is fun, exciting, and adventurous. I always find it amazing how much people can accomplish when they work together and are open to change. I always enjoy spending time with my family and my friends.

Experience

Software Engineer at IGT

September 2014 - Present

I currently work on a self organizing team to complete various projects effectively and efficiently. Use of Agile methodology is encouraged and exercised by my team. I brought change to my team and I attempted to challenge and improve many existing processes that were in place prior to my hire. I have grown and developed as a leader, as a software engineer, and as an individual in my current role. I lead whenever I have an opportunity to do so and I consider myself as an effective, ambitious, driven, optimistic and understanding leader. I really enjoy being challenged by my teammates because I push myself to be better and to perform at my best every single day. Projects I worked on range from API, web, automation, and database development to server and environment maintenance and support.

Technical Compliance Test Engineer at Ainsworth Game Technology

January 2014 - September 2014 (9 months)

Identified software anomalies and worked with the game developers on resolutions. Performed various math calculations to verify game's algorithms and odds. Verified, investigated and tested software performance and functionality. Cooperated with the external testing facilities and regulators regarding game submissions and issues. Managed multiple projects at the same time and prioritized accordingly.

Engineering Intern at NV Energy

May 2012 - December 2013 (1 year 8 months)

Worked in Energy Efficiency and Demand Response, and Distribution and Operation departments. Operated load control systems and collaborated with the engineering personnel to target load reduction at the electrical system peaks. Developed and performed testing procedure for In Home Displays. Provided technical support to transmission and distribution operators. Dealt with Energy Management System (EMS) and Distribution Management System (DMS).

Education

University of Nevada-Las Vegas

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Marketing, 2014 - 2016

University of Nevada-Las Vegas

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Engineering, 2009 - 2014

Aleksandar Jovkovic

Software Engineer at International Game Technology



Contact Aleksandar on LinkedIn